Please hear me out.
请听我说
-Mother! -Mom!
-妈妈
SCARLET NEXUS
《绯红结系》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立关系的方法吗
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
有个麻烦的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在寻求某人的拥抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虚无之间
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以输赢之间为目标
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
注意别让信任走向尽头 务必小心
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你脑中那冷感的轨道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
摇滚的日子未曾有过的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光荣早已埋葬在某处
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
这一瞬间寂寞孤独的野兽
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世间道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地联系着
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那脑中冷感的正义
REUNION
(重逢)
Kasane, what did you call her just now?
重 妳刚才叫她什么
She is my mother. Yuito, but you...
我叫她妈妈 结人你才是
Why did you call her mother as well?
为何也叫她妈妈
I missed both of you.
我好想见你们喔
Don't be tricked. That is a image created by BABE.
别被迷惑 那是贝比做出来的影像
Wakana is a noble person.
若菜是尊贵的人
She is one of the design children who possessed the Red Strings.
她是拥有红色系线脑力的设计孩童
My mother was one of the design children?
妈妈是设计孩童
She was the beacon of hope to realize our dream.
她是能达成我们愿望的希望
Yuito and Kasane,
而结人 重
she is your loved one.
对你们来说 也是重要的人
If I remember correctly, Wakana was your instructor, Kasane.
若菜 好像是负责教导重的人
But she died in a certain incident in Togetsu.
但听说因为某个事件 在渡月丧命了
I hope you find happiness in the future.
希望 妳拥有幸福的未来
Did she escape Togetsu and meet with Yuito's father in Suoh?
阿姨 从渡月逃到苏芳 与叔叔相遇啰
Or perhaps she was under Suoh's protection.
又或是 被苏芳保护
Chairman Sumeragi knew this woman.
皇议长 知道这位女性
He knew she was connected to Togetsu.
知道若菜小姐 是渡月的关系人…
-This is surprising. -This is a little hard to believe.
-真令人讶异 -感觉好奇特
To beckon the two of you,
为了呼唤两人
I thought this is the best form I should take.
我认为这个姿态最为妥当
Yuito and Kasane, you both understand
结人 重 你们知道吧
the crisis brought about by the expanding Kunad Gate.
现在正因岐之门而陷入灭亡危机
Your help is needed to save the world from annihilation.
为了拯救世界 急需两人的帮忙
Our help?
帮忙…
Yuito, I'm sorry I left you when you were just a child.
结人 对不起 丢下还年幼的你
But I will make up for your loneliness.
但我会好好弥补你的寂寞
Kasane, do you still remember the puppy?
重 还记得那只小狗吗
At this rate, all of us will die.
再这样下去大家都会死的
People of the world are just like that puppy.
世界众人 就像那只小狗一样…
Will you listen to my wish?
两位 肯听听我的愿望吗
Don't use my mother for your own plotting!
别擅自为你们的计划 而利用我妈妈
You plan to eliminate the whole world along with the history of those immigrants.
你们打算将世间众人 连同移民历史一起毁灭
Mother would never want that.
这绝非妈妈所望
Fools.
愚蠢
After we retrieved the brain of your beloved Wakana,
回收深爱你们的若菜的脑部后
she had already become part of me.
她早就与我合一了
What?
妳说什么
Does it mean BABE is integrated with human brains?
难道贝比中 还结合了人脑吗
Mom didn't die in an Other attack.
妈妈不是被怪异袭击而身亡
She died because of BABE and Togetsu!
而是被贝比… 被你们渡月… 把妈妈的…
This is for the world's salvation.
这都是为了救赎世界
Cut the salvation nonsense.
救赎个头啦
You only say that because you get to profit from it.
这只是对你们有利的说法吧
You can never use my mother to sway our resolve.
你们是无法利用妈妈来动摇我们
You are trying to stop us from moving forward.
你们想阻止我们前进吧
I won't allow you to tarnish my mother's memory.
我不许你们再利用妈妈
We have to stop BABE.
必须 停止贝比
Did the Kunad Gate just expand?
岐之门又扩大了吗
This is...
这是…
Get out of here! This place is collapsing!
大家快跑 要崩塌了
Togetsu have finally shown their true color.
看来渡月终于露出真面目了
It's not over just yet!
还没完吗
Tsugumi, there seems to be a teleportation point somewhere.
鸫 有没有看起来像传送点的地方
There is nothing else except for this path.
除了这条路之外 什么都没有
Just keep running!
总之 别停下脚步
-Yuito! -I got it!
-结人 -好
Leave it to me.
交给我吧
-Everyone is fine. -That was close.
-大家好像都没事 -太好了
Over there!
那里
Run faster!
动作快
At least we won't fall to our death now.
看来我们不会摔死了
This place isn't going to collapse, right?
不会再崩塌了吧
Don't worry, this is BABE itself.
别担心 那就是贝比的本体
We can have access to all areas of BABE from here.
这里 应该能登入贝比中所有区域
We can certainly stop it from here as well.
当然也能停止贝比的机能
This is...
这是…
What's wrong?
怎么了
For a second there, I could feel the Red Strings.
刚才那瞬间 类似红色系线的感觉
Arashi, what's wrong?
岚 怎么样
This is quite a surprise.
这真是令人惊讶啊
What we see here is just a husk.
这只是个空壳
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
I mean it literally.
就是字面上的意思
There isn't a trace of anything left.
无留下任何痕迹
The data has been wiped.
数据被删除得一乾二净
All that is left for us to see is an shadow.
只留下了执念
You mean,
意思是说
BABE surrendered and wiped the data on its own?
贝比认输 自己删除所有数据吗
Now that BABE has been shut down, Togetsu is no longer a threat to us.
贝比停止机能了 就表示渡月已无任何威胁
However, I doubt they would give up so easily.
但我不觉得渡月 会这么简单就放弃
It's frustrating,
虽然无法释怀
but at least now we can confirm
但现在至少能确定
there is no information we can extract from this computer.
这部计算机已没有内容物
It's just an empty husk.
只是个空壳
Indeed.
对
Is everyone all right?
你们没事吧
If it isn't Wataru.
是渡啊
The communication is back online.
既然恢复通讯
Which can only mean BABE has been shut down.
就表示贝比确实停止机能了
I'm glad you managed to stop BABE.
你们停止了贝比 太好了
We have detected more anomalies of the Kunad Gate.
又观察到岐之门出现异常
It's happening a little too frequently.
最近的频率有点频繁
We put an end to Togetsu's plan,
虽然阻止了渡月的计划
but the data here have been wiped.
但里面的资料也全部消失了
We could have found some useful information about the Kunad Gate.
原本里面可能存有 跟岐之门相关的资料…
Kagero, Kyoka,
阳炎 镜花
are there any other places that store research data or someone who knows them?
是否还有存放研究资料的地方 或熟悉资料的人
The Red Strings are power full of mysteries.
"红色系线" 本身就是充满谜团的超脑力
I doubt anyone has any comprehensive information about it.
应该没人掌握完整信息吧
It can't be...
怎么会…
Is there nothing we can do now?
那就没辙了吗
There is someone that can help us.
我想到一个人
It's Wakana.
就是若菜小姐
She had the Red Strings and she was your caretaker.
拥有红色系线 又负责照顾重的人
Which means she had the knowledge to raise Kasane into
这就表示 她拥有将重培育成
someone capable of wielding the power of Red Strings.
红色系线超脑力者的相关知识吧
Don't be silly, she is already...
说什么傻话 阿姨她…
I get it.
原来如此
The quickest way is to ask her.
直接问她最快对吧
It's massive.
原本有这么大吗
There is no doubt that thing is growing.
看来 岐之门正在扩大
Are you really going to use the Red Strings?
妳真的要使用红色系线
Yes. That is the only option we have left.
对 我们能采取的手段 只剩下这个了
But that will exert more stress to Yuito's brain.
可是 这样又会 给结人的脑部带来负担
If we do nothing,
什么都不做的话
the Kunad Gate will keep expanding.
岐之门会持续扩大
The world will be destroyed.
世界只会走向灭亡
Despite the risk, I must try every option we have.
就算不行 我也想尝试各种可能
We'll do our best to help.
那我们只能协助你了
Coming here reminds me of so many things.
来到这 让我想起许多事
The Red Strings...
红色系线…
I think we can do this.
我觉得 应该可行
I see.
这样啊
I wish I could sense that.
如果 我也有这种感应就好了
We will assist you with SAS.
我们用SAS协助你们
Yes, thank you.
好 谢谢
Do you have an exact time and date where you can meet Wakana?
有没有能确实见到若菜小姐的时日
It's October 4th, 2009.
2009年10月4日
It's at an old OSF hospital of Lokusho City.
绿青市的旧怪伐军医院
We can surely meet her there.
去那里 一定见得到
The Others attacked Lokusho City on that day.
是绿青市受到怪异袭击的日子
It's also the day my mother died.
也是我母亲的忌日
Try to recall
仔细回想
the time and place.
那天 和地点
Yes. But my memories about the past are a little foggy.
好 可是我记不清以前的事了
Don't worry, you have us.
放心 不是只有我们
Everyone is here for you.
还有大家在
You've grown a little mature.
看来妳也有点成长嘛
Thanks to someone.
托了某人的福啊
However, I should go alone.
不过 我一个人回到过去就好
Kasane...
重
Except for the user of the Red Strings,
除了红色系线的超脑力者
everyone else will be sent back here after a certain amount of time.
其他人过一段时间就会被强制送回
Considering the damages it could do to your brain,
考虑到给脑部带来的负担
I should go alone.
人越少越好
No, I must go with you.
不行 我也要一起去
It's too dangerous to let you go there alone.
妳一个人太危险了
No.
不
Yuito was still young back then.
当时的结人还年幼
There is no telling what might happen
同一人物在同个时空相遇
when two different you meet.
不知会发生什么事
This is just an assumption,
虽然这只是个假设
but let's not take any risks.
但最好还是避开风险吧
But if Kasane go there alone...
可是 重一个人去实在是…
Don't worry. I won't be alone.
放心 我不是一个人
With you who has the same power staying here in the present,
而且 拥有相同脑力的你留在这
I can use you to find my way back.
也能成为我回到现代的路标
That's what I think.
我是这么想的
You want me to act as a wayfinder.
我是指路的灯塔啰
But don't overdo it.
好 但妳绝不能勉强喔
Yes, you have my word.
好 我保证
Let's begin.
开始吧
Yuito! Are you all right?
结人 没事吧
Yuito! Wake up!
结人 醒醒啊
Yuito!
结人…
Yuito, you tried your best.
结人 你很努力喔
You did great.
很棒喔
Do you remember what day it is?
记得今天是什么日子啊
It's the children's party!
是儿童派对的日子
Yes! There will be a feast tonight.
对 晚上有丰盛的料理喔
I have a present for you too, Yuito.
而且 我也有礼物要送你喔
What is it?
是什么
You'll find out tonight.
晚上再揭晓喔
Do you want to see it now?
等不及了吗
Well, before that, let's play.
好 在这之前跟妈妈一起玩吧
How is that boy doing?
那位少年的情况如何
There is no signs of any changes.
还没有变化的征兆
But the process of treating Bell Peppers varies with each person.
不过 治疗甜椒的过程 也是有个人差异的
Yuito really was a Bell Pepper.
结人 果然是…
-Are you ready? -Not yet!
-躲好了吗 -还没唷
-Don't go too far away. -Yes!
-不能跑太远喔 -好
I'm ready!
躲好了
Where are you now?
你躲到哪去了呢
Over here?
是这里吗
Where could you be?
在哪呢
I am...
我是…
It's really you, Kasane.
妳果然是重
One day, I received memories from the future.
有天 我突然接收到未来的记忆
In the memories, I saw you in Togetsu.
记忆中 我看见妳到渡月的身影
BABE was right.
这算是 贝比赌赢了吧
You proved the Red Strings' possibilities.
妳证明了红色系线的可能性
Mother, what is going on?
妈妈 这是怎么回事
BABE's mainframe is connected to the brains of past Red Strings users.
贝比的中枢 连结着 过去红色系线脑力者的脑部
None was as powerful as you.
虽然 大家的力量没有妳强
But BABE used those brains
但贝比利用那些脑部
to trigger a phenomenon similar to the Red Strings.
启动疑似"红色系线"的现象
All the data were sent through time
将所有的数据 跨越时空传送出去
to everyone who possessed the Red Strings.
送给过去拥有红色系线脑力的人
The data were sent through time? Could it be...
传送 难道…
My brain was found in the future BABE.
在未来贝比中寻找到我的脑
Then, BABE's data were sent back to the past to me.
并将贝比的数据 传送给现在的我
Is that even possible?
竟然有这种事
Yes.
是啊
That's how I know you are safe.
所以我知道妳还活得好好的
You've grown taller, Kasane.
妳长大了 重
But now is not the time for nostalgia.
不过 现在不是感叹的时候
You're running out of time.
妳没时间了吧
Mother, thank you.
妈妈 谢谢妳
If you know anything about the Kunad Gate, please tell me.
如果妳知道关于岐之门的事 请告诉我
Is killing Yuito the only way to close the Kunad Gate?
要消除岐之门 真的只能杀了结人吗
Yes.
是的
As long as Yuito lives, the Kunad Gate will eventually consume the world.
结人持续活着 世界就会被岐之门吞噬
No...
怎么这样
I am already ready for it.
所以我已经做好准备了
I must try at the moment when the Red Strings was discovered.
只能趁发现红色系线的当下做尝试
Take me to your timeline.
带我到妳的时代吧
I understand. All I need to do is take you there.
我知道了 只要带妳过去就行了吧
Yes. But before that...
对 不过在这之前
This is a present for Yuito.
这是给结人的礼物
It took great effort to complete.
我好不容易才完成的
This device will protect Yuito from the impact of memories.
这是保护结人受到记忆冲击的装置
It was originally used to mark the patients that needed specialized treatments.
原本 这是用来标示 需管理的特殊病患
But this is special.
但这是特制品
That's Yuito's earring.
结人的耳骨夹
I need to swap this thing with the earring he's wearing now.
和结人现在戴的耳骨夹交换
That should keep him safe.
他就不会有问题了
After that, I'll go with you.
之后 我再跟妳一起走吧
Where is she going?
妈妈要去哪…
Emergency alert!
紧急事态
(OTHER ALERT HAS BEEN ISSUED) Others have been spotted in Lokusho City.
(发布怪异警报) 绿青市出现怪异
Please evacuate to the nearest shelter.
请尽速至避难所避难
Yuito, wait!
结人 等等
Yuito!
结人
-Yuito! -Yuito, where are you?
-结人 -结人你在哪
The shelter is this way!
避难所在这里
Everyone, stay calm and move along.
各位不要慌 冷静行动
Is Yuito inside the shelter?
结人也在避难所里吗
Mother!
妈妈
Are you all right?
没事吧
Yes.
没事
Togetsu...
渡月…
They came this far just to retrieve your brain.
为了回收妈妈的脑追到这里
Mother, look for Yuito inside the shelter.
妈妈到避难所里找结人
I'll look for him somewhere else.
我去别的地方寻找
Very well.
我知道了
But I need you to take this.
但 这个妳帮我拿着
I think it's for the best.
我觉得这样比较好
Well, see you later.
那么 等会儿见啰
Yes.
好
Yuito! Can you hear me?
结人 回妈妈的话
Yuito, stay still!
结人 别动
Great, I made it.
太好了 赶上了
Yuito, I don't have time to explain everything.
结人 我没时间跟你说明了
Put this on.
快戴上这个
Your mother...
妈妈…
This is a gift from your mother.
这是你妈妈送你的礼物
Sure.
好啊
Let me hold it for you.
你帮我拿一下
All right.
好 可以了
You must live on.
你要活下去喔
Stop standing there, go to a shelter!
还愣在那里干嘛 快去避难
Please, take this child to the shelter.
带这孩子到安全的地方
He is Jo Sumeragi's son.
他是条皇的儿子
Yes.
好的
I'll leave him to you.
拜托了
All right, come with us.
好了 我们走吧
Hey, what's wrong?
小朋友 你怎么了
Mother, Yuito put on the earring.
妈妈 我帮结人戴上耳骨夹了
Thank you, Kasane.
谢谢妳 重
-Let's go. -Yes.
-我们走吧 -好
Mom...
妈妈…
Where is Mom?
妈妈在哪
-Mom! -Stay still!
-妈妈 -别乱动
Mom!
妈妈
Yuito, are you all right?
结人 你没事吧
I knew it.
果然
You must live on.
你要活下去喔
Is that...
那是…
Mom!
妈妈
Yuito.
结人
I found you.
找到你了
Mom...
妈妈
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭开被阻挡的摇曳阳炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
从未见过
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐惧翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
华丽舞步的鸟儿
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染红的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追过了强风
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千变万化的世界里
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交错的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持续寻找明天的行径方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前进
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏惧何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
WAKANA'S RESOLVE
(若菜的决心)